<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fantasy-literature on Seth Green&#39;s personal website</title>
    <link>/tags/fantasy-literature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fantasy-literature on Seth Green&#39;s personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/fantasy-literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>All the words in &#39;Lord of the Rings&#39; that I did not know</title>
      <link>/2020/07/22/all-the-words-in-lord-of-the-rings-that-i-did-not-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/22/all-the-words-in-lord-of-the-rings-that-i-did-not-know/</guid>
      <description>Sixty-four in all! I had a sense of what some of these meant but included them if I wasn’t pretty sure, and a lot of the usages were archaic.
The joy of putting together a list like this was both learning a bunch of fun words and also engaging with the people who have tread before me in the task of understanding LOTR minutiae, e.g., the folks who wrote the Tolkien Glossary and Tolkien and the OED.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pleasure of the Appendices of the Lord of the Rings</title>
      <link>/2020/05/25/the-pleasure-of-the-appendices-of-the-lord-of-the-rings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/25/the-pleasure-of-the-appendices-of-the-lord-of-the-rings/</guid>
      <description>Author’s Note: This post isn’t going to make a lot of sense if you aren’t already familiar with LOTR, The Hobbit, etc.
In the foreword to the second edition of The Lord of the Rings, Tolkien writes:
 It is perhaps not possible in a long tale to please everybody at all points, nor to displease everybody at the same points; for I find from the letters that I have received that the passages or chapters that are to some a blemish are all by others specially approved.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>