<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Movies on Seth Ariel Green&#39;s website</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/movies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Movies on Seth Ariel Green&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 11:53:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Bad Hombres&#39; movies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/bad-hombres-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/bad-hombres-movies/</guid>
      <description>It’s a conservative trope that Hollywood hates Trump, Republicans, and all they hold dear. But we still get movies with fundamentally Trump-y themes animating them. Consider what we might call the ‘bad hombres’ genre:&#xA;Silent Night, in which a (white) man seeks vengeance against (Latino) gangsters in southern California after they kill his son Peppermint, which has the same plot except it stars Jennifer Garner Brawl in Cell Block 99, in which some bad, multicultural gangsters try to ruin Vince Vaughn’s life because he’s prudent and ethically grounded (apparently its studio has a populist bent) …probably others I haven’t seen (ChatGPT suggests The Marksman, Rambo: Last Blood, and Sicario).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The office drone who would be king: 1999 in cinema</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-office-drone-who-would-be-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-office-drone-who-would-be-king/</guid>
      <description>According to readers of the New York Times, the top four movies of 1999 were The Matrix, Fight Club, Office Space, and American Beauty. I love this selection because I think they’re all basically the same movie, starring basically one character:&#xA;The movie goes like this:&#xA;An office schlub encounters a mythical stranger who teaches him that rules of reality are optional. He decides to stop playing along and immediately becomes cool, popular, and powerful: a middle-aged ubermensch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five observations about &#34;The Substance&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/five-observations-about-the-substance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/five-observations-about-the-substance/</guid>
      <description>I would have enjoyed this movie a bit more with some tighter editing, less repetition, and more leavening humor. But I did enjoy it. Diana Stevens, who shares some of my concerns, didn’t.&#xA;This movie is basically Fight Club with no good/bad distinction between the halves of the self. (Although Fight Club is also a little confused about this because it’s so horny for Brad Pitt.) Sarah Gorr makes the same connection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venom, an emotionally self-aware ubermensch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/venom-an-emotionally-self-aware-ubermensch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/venom-an-emotionally-self-aware-ubermensch/</guid>
      <description>I have a soft spot for movies that get away from their creators.1 I don’t think that Tony Scott, for instance, intended Top Gun to be a quintessentially gay movie. I think instead that he longed for a richer set of homosocial relationships, where men can like, love, hate, compete, fight, make up, and simply be close to one another all the time. Ancient people would not have questioned this, nor its obvious erotic overtones; the collective unconscious emerges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contagion and A.I., a parable and a fairy tale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/contagion-and-a-i-overt-and-oblique-animal-rights-parables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/contagion-and-a-i-overt-and-oblique-animal-rights-parables/</guid>
      <description>Contagion got a lot of attention these past few years for being eerily predictive and apparently inspiring some aspects of the UK’s pandemic response. I watched it last night, and it is indeed unnerving. I like the shots that lingered on high-touch surfaces; Sodenbergh knows that you’re thinking of all the times you’ve been in all-too-close proximity with a sick person, and all the residue they leave behind.&#xA;But the movie really came together for me in its last 80 seconds, which show a bulldozer destroying a bat’s habitat, who then settles into a pigpen and infects a pig, who is then taken away, killed off-screen, and prepared for consumption by a chef who poses for a photo with Gwyneth Paltrow’s character as the words ‘Day 1’ appear on-screen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re: Baudrillard on Dead Ringers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/baudrillard-kind-of-missed-the-point-of-dead-ringers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/baudrillard-kind-of-missed-the-point-of-dead-ringers/</guid>
      <description>In The Vital Illusion, Jean Baudrillard writes:&#xA;A sort of anticipation of cloning can be found in nature itself, in the phenomenon of twins and twinship (gemellité). We can perceive a kind of cloning in the hallucinatory redoubling of the same, in the primitive symmetry that makes the two twins seem to be like two halves of a single self, of the same individual—and we escape the phantasm only by way of a break, a rupture of the symmetry.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
