<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Seth Green&#39;s personal website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Seth Green&#39;s personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Despicableness as Context</title>
      <link>/2020/07/30/despicableness-as-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/30/despicableness-as-context/</guid>
      <description>Wagner’s antisemitism1 doesn’t bother me when I listen to his music because, at least for the music of his that I know, I don’t see any connection between his hatred for Jews and the text. Ride of the Valkyries works as an independent statement of grandeur. But when R. Kelly sings
 My mind’s tellin’ me no, but my body, my body’s tellin’ me yes
 it reads like a defense of his horrible behavior; the context of his despicableness suffuses the text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rstudio as a Python IDE</title>
      <link>/2020/07/22/rstudio-as-a-python-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/22/rstudio-as-a-python-ide/</guid>
      <description>So far, I’ve found it pretty viable. I am a Python n00b but used it a bit to create my last post (source .Rmd here).
The main advantage is that it brings all the key bindings I’m used to. YMMV, but I also really like how easy Rstudio makes it to execute code as I’m iterating, whether in a script or the interpreter. As far as I know, there’s no “Python-first” IDE that does this as well as Rstudio does this for R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the words in Lord of the Rings that I did not know</title>
      <link>/2020/07/21/all-the-words-in-lord-of-the-rings-that-i-did-not-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/21/all-the-words-in-lord-of-the-rings-that-i-did-not-know/</guid>
      <description>Sixty-four in all! I had a sense of what some of these meant but included them if I wasn’t pretty sure, and a lot of the usages were archaic.
The joy of putting together a list like this was both learning a bunch of fun words and also engaging with the people who have tread before me in understanding LOTR minutiae, e.g., the folks who wrote the Tolkien Glossary and Tolkien and the OED.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rihanna &amp; Borges; or, when Rihanna covers &#34;Same Ol&#39; Mistakes,&#34;</title>
      <link>/2020/07/09/rihanna-borges-or-when-rihanna-covers-same-ol-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/09/rihanna-borges-or-when-rihanna-covers-same-ol-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>she imparts to the text the full weight of her celebrity. The words
 Finally taking flight
I know you don’t think it’s right
I know that you think it’s fake
Maybe fake’s what I like
 become rich with the overtones of her many personas: badgirlriri, the world’s richest woman musician, the CEO of a huge corporation – a person who has lived half her life under unbearable scrutiny, here, acknowledging the burden of making art that appeals to the median human.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing takes a long time</title>
      <link>/2020/07/09/writing-takes-a-long-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/09/writing-takes-a-long-time/</guid>
      <description>My previous post is 557 words, and about 70% of them are either Borges’s or Kevin Parker’s; it took me about 5 hours to compose and properly format it (and hours of hiking alone to stumble upon the connection between the subjects). I’ll probably get faster as I get more accustomed to both this style of writing and markdown syntax, but still, damn. I’m all the more impressed by other writers’ speed and volume of ouptut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contra Robin Hanson and Jeff Kaufman on veganism</title>
      <link>/2020/05/30/contra-robin-hanson-and-jeff-kaufman-on-veganism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/30/contra-robin-hanson-and-jeff-kaufman-on-veganism/</guid>
      <description>Observations, and arguments worth responding to:
Michael Huemer observes – in Dialogues on Ethical Vegetarianism, and in a recent Cato Unbound series on What moral considerations do humans owe animals – three things that I agree with and think about a lot:
 Eating meat is the worst thing that he has ever done (I think this is true for me as well); Factory farming is at least a plausible contender for the most important ethical issue today; “Given that nearly every person in America buys animal products from factory farms on a regular basis, it should be easy to find someone to defend the morality of that practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Open Data and Computational Reproducibility in Registered Reports in Psychology</title>
      <link>/2020/05/25/analysis-of-open-data-and-computational-reproducibility-in-registered-reports-in-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/25/analysis-of-open-data-and-computational-reproducibility-in-registered-reports-in-psychology/</guid>
      <description>was published last week, on which yours truly is a co-author.
Its abstract (emphasis added):
 Ongoing technological developments have made it easier than ever before for scientists to share their data, materials, and analysis code. Sharing data and analysis code makes it easier for other researchers to reuse or check published research. However, these benefits will emerge only if researchers can reproduce the analyses reported in published articles and if data are annotated well enough so that it is clear what all variable and value labels mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pleasure of the Appendices of the Lord of the Rings</title>
      <link>/2020/05/25/the-pleasure-of-the-appendices-of-the-lord-of-the-rings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/25/the-pleasure-of-the-appendices-of-the-lord-of-the-rings/</guid>
      <description>Author’s Note: This post isn’t going to make a lot of sense if you aren’t already familiar with LOTR, The Hobbit, etc.
In the foreword to the second edition of The Lord of the Rings, Tolkien writes:
 It is perhaps not possible in a long tale to please everybody at all points, nor to displease everybody at the same points; for I find from the letters that I have received that the passages or chapters that are to some a blemish are all by others specially approved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Florida doing a great job handling things?</title>
      <link>/2020/05/22/is-florida-doing-a-great-job-handling-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/22/is-florida-doing-a-great-job-handling-things/</guid>
      <description>Rich Lowry thinks so. He interviews Ron DeSantis and his colleagues, who seem to have focused on keeping very vulerable people in nursing homes safe, and frames the piece as “liberal media can’t admit that Trump-friendly guy is doing a good job.”1
First question: what is the general consensus on Florida’s COVID response? When I searched Google News for “Florida” and “Coronavirus,” I found little that evalauted its overall response, but a lot of stories about a Florida data scientist who was apparently fired for not faking the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are NYC apartment prices not falling more?</title>
      <link>/2020/05/21/why-are-nyc-apartment-prices-not-falling-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/21/why-are-nyc-apartment-prices-not-falling-more/</guid>
      <description>Observations:  I have an apartment in New York. I don’t currently reside there and will move out when the lease ends (in about a month). Many people I know are in the same boat (and we know there’s been something of an exodus from the city).  This feels like it should be a major supply-demand readjustment. But prices don’t seem to reflect that.
Browsing rentals on StreetEasy, prices seem to have fallen slightly from where they were three months ago – despite New York’s being the epicenter of a pandemic, and therefore:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>