<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Seth Ariel Green&#39;s website</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Seth Ariel Green&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 09:13:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Date Me Docs, obviously</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/date-me-docs-obviously/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/date-me-docs-obviously/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote a date me doc – see here for context. (I continue to be belatedly zeitgeisty.)&#xA;To me, the case that single people should do this is self-evident: why not? what are the costs? But a few pieces of social context made writing one seem not just desirable but advisable:&#xA;To dating apps — increasingly owned and run by one megacorp — we are the product, not the client.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meaningfully reducing meat consumption is an unsolved problem: meta-analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/meaningfully-reducing-consumption-of-meat-and-animal-products-is-an-unsolved-problem-a-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/meaningfully-reducing-consumption-of-meat-and-animal-products-is-an-unsolved-problem-a-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I am co-author on a new meta-analysis about interventions aimed at reducing consumption of meat and animal products. We conclude that no theoretical approach, delivery mechanism, or persuasive message should be considered a well-validated means of reducing MAP consumption.&#xA;Here is&#xA;the paper;&#xA;a summary on the EA forum;&#xA;our code and data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Bad Hombres&#39; movies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/bad-hombres-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/bad-hombres-movies/</guid>
      <description>It’s a conservative trope that Hollywood hates Trump, Republicans, and all they hold dear. But we still get movies with fundamentally Trump-y themes animating them. Consider what we might call the ‘bad hombres’ genre:&#xA;Silent Night, in which a (white) man seeks vengeance against (Latino) gangsters in southern California after they kill his son Peppermint, which has the same plot except it stars Jennifer Garner Brawl in Cell Block 99, in which some bad, multicultural gangsters try to ruin Vince Vaughn’s life because he’s prudent and ethically grounded (apparently its studio has a populist bent) …probably others I haven’t seen (ChatGPT suggests The Marksman, Rambo: Last Blood, and Sicario).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A few salient election details</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/a-few-salient-election-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/a-few-salient-election-details/</guid>
      <description>Of the many, these stick out:&#xA;Harris got zero votes in 2020 because she has no natural constituency and isn’t good at campaigning. Why would things have been different this time?&#xA;Trump is what McCain wanted to be, a true maverick. Getting Tulsi Gabbard and RFK Jr. onboard — dominating the crank vote without alienating mainstream Republicans — is remarkable.&#xA;Democrats have bungled governance, over and over. Last year we learned that California has apparently always been capable of making San Francisco a nice place to walk around, but only did so to impress President Xi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factory farming as a bodybuilding hard problem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/factory-farming-bodybuilding-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/factory-farming-bodybuilding-hard/</guid>
      <description>Alex Crompton introduces a useful distinction between a ‘math hard’ problem, where the solution is hard to come up with but easy to copy, and a ‘bodybuilding hard’ problem, where the solution is easy to come up with and hard to copy.&#xA;Math hard problems also pose an additional challenge: you don’t know in advance if there is a correct solution at all, or the right way to make progress on finding it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The office drone who would be king: 1999 in cinema</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-office-drone-who-would-be-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-office-drone-who-would-be-king/</guid>
      <description>According to readers of the New York Times, the top four movies of 1999 were The Matrix, Fight Club, Office Space, and American Beauty. I love this selection because I think they’re all basically the same movie, starring basically one character:&#xA;The movie goes like this:&#xA;An office schlub encounters a mythical stranger who teaches him that rules of reality are optional. He decides to stop playing along and immediately becomes cool, popular, and powerful: a middle-aged ubermensch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The gazpacho, it scalds me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-gazpacho-it-scalds-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-gazpacho-it-scalds-me/</guid>
      <description>When an I Think You Should Leave skit takes me a long time to warm up to, it’s usually because the situation for which it’s a perfect rejoinder hasn’t come my way yet.&#xA;This week, I thought a lot about poor Howie from the charades skit. He wants to enjoy some Gazpacho, but&#xA;Howie: This gazpacho soup just burned my lips.&#xA;chorus: The gazpacho?&#xA;Howie: Yeah, it’s been sitting out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five observations about &#34;The Substance&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/five-observations-about-the-substance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/five-observations-about-the-substance/</guid>
      <description>I would have enjoyed this movie a bit more with some tighter editing, less repetition, and more leavening humor. But I did enjoy it. Diana Stevens, who shares some of my concerns, didn’t.&#xA;This movie is basically Fight Club with no good/bad distinction between the halves of the self. (Although Fight Club is also a little confused about this because it’s so horny for Brad Pitt.) Sarah Gorr makes the same connection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My spunky milieu, childless Brooklyn </title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/my-milieu-childless-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/my-milieu-childless-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>I have noticed recently that I seem to be part of a distinct demographic group without a name.&#xA;My friend Jacob and I came up with Spunk: Sporty Professional Urbanist, No Kids.&#xA;We are:&#xA;Ages 30-45 Living in Brooklyn, SF, etc. Thoroughly professional managerial class Possessed of omnivorous tastes Very physically active (running, climbing, skating, etc. ) Readers (you can find us at book bars) Joiners of clubs and leagues Childless (maybe kids are on the long-term agenda, maybe not) Politically liberal but market urbanists on housing, public transport, and bike lanes Reasonably successful at work but not workaholics Pretty good at our hobbies but not elite Without a singular dominant interest in our lives Occasionally experiencing the lifestyles of much richer people (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD also seems a bit adrift</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/amd-also-seems-to-be-floundering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/amd-also-seems-to-be-floundering/</guid>
      <description>Intel recently announced a plan to eliminate 15,000 jobs after historically bad quarterly results.&#xA;It’s been rehearsed to death that Intel missed the boat on mobile and AI, but execution issues seem just as important to the story. When Apple ditched Intel for its own processors in 2020 to glowing reviews, the root cause was quality assurance. Even if Apple was a small, difficult customer, more alert leadership might have seen their departure as a canary in the coal mine and moved heaven and earth to fix QA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Would that every great artist had a dance music period</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/2024-07-15-would-that-every-great-artist-had-a-disco-period/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/2024-07-15-would-that-every-great-artist-had-a-disco-period/</guid>
      <description>I saw RJD2 spin a few weeks ago, and I was very pleased to hear him play The Who’s Eminence Front, a great, dance-y track whose keyboards evoke (for me) Steve Reich’s Four Organs or the opening theme to Nausicaä. Among great rock artists pivoting to dance music, I’d put this track second in my personal pantheon, behind only Paul McCarthey’s Temporary Secretary, which, as far as I know, sounds like nothing else ever recorded.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My circuitous, undirected career path</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/my-circuitous-undirected-career-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/my-circuitous-undirected-career-path/</guid>
      <description>Something I wrote for the EA forum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extraordinary cost-effectiveness analyses call for supporting theory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/extraordinary-ceas-require-theoretical-buttressing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/extraordinary-ceas-require-theoretical-buttressing/</guid>
      <description>A new post on the EA forum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My talk on &#39;Nudges, Norms, and Persuasion Approaches to Reducing Consumption of Meat and Animal Products&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/my-talk-on-nudges-norms-and-persuasion-approaches-to-reducing-consumption-of-meat-and-animal-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/my-talk-on-nudges-norms-and-persuasion-approaches-to-reducing-consumption-of-meat-and-animal-products/</guid>
      <description>I recently presented an in-progress paper at the Humane and Sustainable Food Lab, where I will be taking a research scientist job starting on July 1st.&#xA;The recording is on YouTube and the slides are here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five agreeable-sounding propositions about housing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/agreeable-housing-propositions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/agreeable-housing-propositions/</guid>
      <description>Bryan Caplan asks us to think about ending zoning, while Manville, Monkkonen &amp;amp; Lens (2019) advocate for ending single-family zoning. I share these priorities, but I think they sound disruptive. Here are five propositions about housing and construction that, I hope, sound more agreeable.&#xA;If a single-family home is ok, a duplex, triplex, in-law suite, or cottage court are all probably ok too.1&#xA;Cities with a wide variety of housing are fun to walk around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Someone to sit in your chair/To ruin your sleep&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/being-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/being-alive/</guid>
      <description>Some thoughts.&#xA;In Being Alive, Bobby enumerates deep and shallow reasons to stay single. Paul responds: there’s more than that. He’s right, but I also think: those things are important because they’re true, because they’re real.&#xA;“A person like Bob doesn’t have the good things and he doesn’t have the bad things, but he doesn’t have the good things,” I get it.&#xA;On Adventure Time, Prismo says: “when I’m alone I can just sit on the couch and when I’m hungry I can eat whatever I want.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sexual violence prevention programs change ideas, not behaviors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/sv-prevention-meta-few-key-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/sv-prevention-meta-few-key-points/</guid>
      <description>I am a co-author on a new meta-analysis: Preventing Sexual Violence —A Behavioral Problem Without a Behaviorally-Informed Solution, along with Roni Porat, Ana P. Gantman, John-Henry Pezzuto, and Elizabeth Levy Paluck.&#xA;The vast majority of papers try to change ideas about sexual violence and are moderately successful at that. However, on the most crucial outcomes — perpetration and victimization — the primary prevention literature has not yet found its footing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if college sports were focused on public health?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/what-if-college-sports-were-focused-on-public-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/what-if-college-sports-were-focused-on-public-health/</guid>
      <description>In college I played chamber music and ran track and cross country (XC). While both were subsidized by the school, playing music has positive spillovers both for the community (people got to see our concerts) and into the future (e.g. something about how a meaningful life involves making art). Track &amp;amp; XC had, to a first approximation, zero positive benefits for the community at large. (Track meets are boring and XC meets are boring and far away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deleting social media creates (welcome) barriers to returning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/no-more-infinity-scroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/no-more-infinity-scroll/</guid>
      <description>Like many people, I am troubled by my relationship with screens, particularly my phone’s. I am trying three remedies. First, I use my phone in grayscale, like Lorde. Second, I avoid screens from Friday sundown to Saturday sundown.1 Third, I deactivated my Facebook and Instagram accounts, logged out of LinkedIn and Twitter, and deleted Reddit from my phone. For LinkedIn and Twitter, I deleted my passwords so I’d have to go through a recovery process to log in again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venom, an emotionally self-aware ubermensch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/venom-an-emotionally-self-aware-ubermensch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/venom-an-emotionally-self-aware-ubermensch/</guid>
      <description>I have a soft spot for movies that get away from their creators.1 I don’t think that Tony Scott, for instance, intended Top Gun to be a quintessentially gay movie. I think instead that he longed for a richer set of homosocial relationships, where men can like, love, hate, compete, fight, make up, and simply be close to one another all the time. Ancient people would not have questioned this, nor its obvious erotic overtones; the collective unconscious emerges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards richly annotated digital books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/richly-annotated-digital-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/richly-annotated-digital-books/</guid>
      <description>I am reading Lord of the Rings again and, as always, there are many words, phrases and names I don’t know. But this time I am reading digitally, so when Denethor talks about “Vorondil father of Mardil” who “hunted the wild kine of Araw in the far fields of Rhûnm,” I can at least look up ‘Vorondil’ and cross-check his place in the appendix.&#xA;Even better would be an easy way to pull up and cross-check the Tolkien Gateway, the Interactive Middle-Earth map, or perhaps Andy Serkis’s off-kilter renditions of Tom Bombadil’s songs in a way that allows the reader to luxuriate in the details without losing their place in the text.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five categories of social adversary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/five-categories-of-social-adversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/five-categories-of-social-adversary/</guid>
      <description>When trying to explain a social problem, we might argue any of the following:&#xA;Those people are bad, e.g. blame the capitalists for global warming, the poor for their predicament, or the Jews for “a whole range of things…from the world war to short skirts to jazz music.”&#xA;That policy is harmful, e.g. a minimum wage might “price working poor people out of the job market.”&#xA;Those people are too radical, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental &amp; health appeals are the most effective vegan outreach strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/reducing-consumption-of-meat-and-animal-products-what-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/reducing-consumption-of-meat-and-animal-products-what-works/</guid>
      <description>Now published on the EA forum, aiming to publish in an academic journal next year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards non-meat diets for domesticated dogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/towards-non-meat-diets-for-domesticated-dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/towards-non-meat-diets-for-domesticated-dogs/</guid>
      <description>An essay I just wrote for the EA forum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fraud is the lack of use cases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-fraud-is-the-lack-of-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-fraud-is-the-lack-of-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>I have been consuming a lot of SBF content lately, e.g. Zvi Mowshowtiz’s review of Going Infinite, David Morris’s comments on FTX’s lawyer, Molly White’s courtroom reporting, and a Bloomberg documentary.&#xA;To summarize the story so far:&#xA;someone(s) working at FTX and/or Alameda set things up to allow Alameda to gamble with FTX customer money. Alameda more or less burned that money on a bunch bets that Number Go Up, AKA that the crypto market would grow monotonically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Manager as a distinct professional class</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/social-media-manager-as-a-distinct-professional-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/social-media-manager-as-a-distinct-professional-class/</guid>
      <description>I have now worked in marketing and marketing-adjacent jobs at two startups, producing blog posts, social media, and external content under the tutelage of two directors of marketing, a head of growth, and a chief marketing officer. I’ve learned that marketing is a quasi-discipline with sacred texts, gurus, widely understood conceptual divisions (I mostly did content marketing, as opposed to product marketing or growth hacking), and dogmas about what tactics are appropriate to which situations (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substack is reader-hostile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/substack-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/substack-sucks/</guid>
      <description>A lot of writers I like have moved to Substack.&#xA;I presume that some of them are doing it for a big payday, e.g. Danny Lavery was kind enough to tell the Times that his 2-year Substack contract was worth $430,000.1 Others say that it multiplied their readership.&#xA;But as a reader, Substack is a big step down from (e.g.) blogspot, wordpress, or self-hosted content. When I click a blogpost, it’s because I want to read it, not</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards ML-literate dystopian fiction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/towards-ml-literate-dystopian-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/towards-ml-literate-dystopian-fiction/</guid>
      <description>My favorite moment in M3gan comes when Allison Williams says to the title character: “I know you think you’re maximizing your objective function.” it was fun to hear an explicit nod to the language of AI-alignment; someone who worked on this movie reads LessWrong, or talked to people who do.&#xA;M3gan could serve as a great prequel to an AI apocalypse movie (though I think it’s unlikely). But thinking those movies over – Terminator, Oblivion, The Matrix – they’re mostly action movies that come down to a test of strength.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GiveWell should fund an SMC replication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/givewell-should-fund-an-smc-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/givewell-should-fund-an-smc-replication/</guid>
      <description>An essay I wrote in response to GiveWell’s “Change Our Mind Contest.”</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traveling North</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/traveling-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/traveling-north/</guid>
      <description>An essay about my friend Danny, and our respective journeys on the Appalachian Trail, published in the spring/summer 2022 issue of A.T. Journeys.&#xA;My original (more stylistically out there) submission is here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UX testing for public infrastructure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/ux-testing-for-public-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/ux-testing-for-public-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>An article in the Wall Street Journal documents LaGuardia Airport’s remarkable turnaround:&#xA;It’s no longer appalling. It’s actually nice. In fact, when a panel of judges recently named the world’s best new airport building, the prestigious honor went to Terminal B.&#xA;The design team ran some “clever experiments” see if things worked like intended:&#xA;One was a live trial in which hundreds of friends and relatives came to a concourse of Terminal B right before it opened in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Having your social justice cake and eating well too</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/having-your-social-justice-cake-and-eating-well-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/having-your-social-justice-cake-and-eating-well-too/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, a friend was doing a prestigious postdoc at a prominent law school. One time, a scholar who was in town for a seminar asked to be taken to a thousand-dollar-a-head restaurant,1 and it was my friend’s responsibility to clear that with their department chair – who promptly said, more or less, “no problem.” So out they went, my friend, the visiting scholar, and a few others; and thus did the school spend something like 10% of a law student’s yearly tuition on a single dinner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contagion and A.I., a parable and a fairy tale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/contagion-and-a-i-overt-and-oblique-animal-rights-parables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/contagion-and-a-i-overt-and-oblique-animal-rights-parables/</guid>
      <description>Contagion got a lot of attention these past few years for being eerily predictive and apparently inspiring some aspects of the UK’s pandemic response. I watched it last night, and it is indeed unnerving. I like the shots that lingered on high-touch surfaces; Sodenbergh knows that you’re thinking of all the times you’ve been in all-too-close proximity with a sick person, and all the residue they leave behind.&#xA;But the movie really came together for me in its last 80 seconds, which show a bulldozer destroying a bat’s habitat, who then settles into a pigpen and infects a pig, who is then taken away, killed off-screen, and prepared for consumption by a chef who poses for a photo with Gwyneth Paltrow’s character as the words ‘Day 1’ appear on-screen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re: Baudrillard on Dead Ringers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/baudrillard-kind-of-missed-the-point-of-dead-ringers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/baudrillard-kind-of-missed-the-point-of-dead-ringers/</guid>
      <description>In The Vital Illusion, Jean Baudrillard writes:&#xA;A sort of anticipation of cloning can be found in nature itself, in the phenomenon of twins and twinship (gemellité). We can perceive a kind of cloning in the hallucinatory redoubling of the same, in the primitive symmetry that makes the two twins seem to be like two halves of a single self, of the same individual—and we escape the phantasm only by way of a break, a rupture of the symmetry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marianne Moore and Dan Harmon, inscrutable to the future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/marianne-moore-and-dan-harmon-future-inscrutables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/marianne-moore-and-dan-harmon-future-inscrutables/</guid>
      <description>My favorite Marianne Moore poems are generally the ones I understand right away, because they’re short, they rhyme, and they’re about animals. I like animals. I like the way she describes rats, chameleons, and talismanic seagulls. Those poems are lovely and easy to digest. It’s a lot more work to figure out what’s going on in, e.g., Diligence is to Magic as Progress Is to Flight, or To a Prize Bird, which, I learned when I looked it up, is actually about George Bernard Shaw.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve been zeitgeisty lately</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/i-ve-been-zeitgeisty-lately/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/i-ve-been-zeitgeisty-lately/</guid>
      <description>I:&#xA;was a zoomtown-er in Park City in October 2020;&#xA;left my job to pursue personal projects in April 2021;&#xA;got an unsanctioned booster shot a few days ago.1&#xA;I wonder if the trend of being trendy will continue? I also am prompted to think about how much the ideas that feel original or appealingly counternormative to me are just ‘in the air.’&#xA;This one I will explain. I got the J&amp;amp;J shot in April 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want my words to tell the story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/i-want-my-words-to-tell-the-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/i-want-my-words-to-tell-the-story/</guid>
      <description>In late summer 2010, I was on a bus one evening in Philadelphia, returning to Swarthmore. A man came on who had the words ‘Fuck em all’ tattooed across his chest. I looked at that man, probably more than was polite or advisable, and thought about it. Every single day, that man woke up and had that attitude branded on his skin. By contrast, I could shave and put on a suit and look at home in a consulting firm; or a tie dye shirt and a hemp necklace and fit in at a music festival.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;I&#39;m an ethical vegan, and not the fun kind&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/i-m-an-ethical-vegan-and-not-the-fun-kind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/i-m-an-ethical-vegan-and-not-the-fun-kind/</guid>
      <description>On an episode of Indian Matchmaking, our hero Nadia meets a potential suitor named Vinay at a restaurant and learns that he keeps to a vegan diet. “It was honestly just curiosity,” he says. “Are you ok if I get…” Nadia trails off. “Oh yeah yeah, of course!” he says. “Like, I grew up non-veg, like uh, thirty-five years of my life is non-veg,” and they laugh about it. It was an awkward moment, but they’ve skated past it, because he’s the cool kind of vegan, not one of those preachy PETA people, heaven forbid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An adjective I think about a lot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/an-adjective-i-think-about-a-lot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/an-adjective-i-think-about-a-lot/</guid>
      <description>In An Electronic Soundtrack for Spiritual Awakening, Kelefa Sanneh calls Jon Hopkins “one of the most celebrated electronic musicians of his generation.” Now, I like Hopkins’s music a lot – Collider, Light Through the Veins, Open Eye Signal, and Emerald Rush are all a lot of fun – but “one of the most celebrated”? I think not, at least, not the way Metro Boomin’s tracks with Future are literally present at celebrations all around America, because he makes, get this, popular music.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s weird that no one on &#34;The Good Place&#34; wants children</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/it-s-bizarre-that-no-one-on-the-good-place-has-or-wants-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/it-s-bizarre-that-no-one-on-the-good-place-has-or-wants-children/</guid>
      <description>(Spoilers for the whole show)&#xA;because the show draws so obviously from conservative, christian beliefs about the purpose of life.&#xA;One of the people I watched The Good Place with speculated that the show features zero children in the afterlife, where most of the action takes place, because no one wants to think about dead kids. I’m fine with that; it is, ultimately, a network sitcom, the kind of show you watch because it offers familiar faces1 and comfortable pleasures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The magic of Steve Reich&#39;s music is that I can process it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-magic-of-steve-reichs-music-is-that-i-can-process-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-magic-of-steve-reichs-music-is-that-i-can-process-it/</guid>
      <description>I would like to be able to hear and reproduce every note of the introduction to Nausicaä of the Valley of the Wind, but it is too dense. For other, simpler parts of the soundtrack, you can find Youtube videos that display all pitches, their duration, and their position on a keyboard. I could more or less transcribe the same portions of the score onto a musical staff by ear, but I can’t do this for the introduction, because simultaneous notes in a timbre (electronic organ) I have little experience with are really hard to tease apart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opposition to unplanned progress, bedrock of our politics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/we-lack-a-consistent-term-for-people-who-oppose-unplanned-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/we-lack-a-consistent-term-for-people-who-oppose-unplanned-progress/</guid>
      <description>An article in the Times reports local opposition to redeveloping Industry City in Brooklyn. In Councilman Menchacha’s letter on the subject:&#xA;I firmly believe housing is a human right and that no one should be forced to leave their home because they can no longer afford to live in their own neighborhood….I and my team are committed to working with everyone in the neighborhood to build on a legacy of community-led and comprehensive planning that creates guaranteed housing and jobs</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despicableness as Context</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/despicableness-as-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/despicableness-as-context/</guid>
      <description>I would like to figure out when and how to engage with artists who are bad people.&#xA;On the one hand, Richard Wagner did not much care for Jews – and not just in the way that was cant for 19th century Germans, but actively going out of his way to disparage Jews and Jewish composers.1 This doesn’t bother me, and I think it’s because I don’t see any connection between his music and his beliefs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All the words in Lord of the Rings that I did not know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/all-the-words-in-lord-of-the-rings-that-i-did-not-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/all-the-words-in-lord-of-the-rings-that-i-did-not-know/</guid>
      <description>Sixty-four in all! I had a sense of what some of these meant but included them if I wasn’t pretty sure, and a lot of the usages were archaic.&#xA;The joy of putting together a list like this was both learning a bunch of fun words and also engaging with the people who have tread before me in understanding LOTR minutiae, e.g., the folks who wrote the Tolkien Glossary and Tolkien and the OED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rihanna &amp; Borges; or, when Rihanna covers &#34;Same Ol&#39; Mistakes,&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/rihanna-borges-or-when-rihanna-covers-same-ol-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/rihanna-borges-or-when-rihanna-covers-same-ol-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>she imparts to the text the full weight of her celebrity. The words&#xA;Finally taking flight&#xA;I know you don’t think it’s right&#xA;I know that you think it’s fake&#xA;Maybe fake’s what I like&#xA;become rich with the overtones of her many personas: badgirlriri, the world’s richest woman musician, the CEO of a huge corporation – a person who has lived half her life under unbearable scrutiny, here, acknowledging the burden of making art that appeals to the median human.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pleasure of the Appendices of the Lord of the Rings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-pleasure-of-the-appendices-of-the-lord-of-the-rings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/the-pleasure-of-the-appendices-of-the-lord-of-the-rings/</guid>
      <description>Author’s Note: This post isn’t going to make a lot of sense if you aren’t already familiar with LOTR, The Hobbit, etc.&#xA;In the foreword to the second edition of The Lord of the Rings, Tolkien writes:&#xA;It is perhaps not possible in a long tale to please everybody at all points, nor to displease everybody at the same points; for I find from the letters that I have received that the passages or chapters that are to some a blemish are all by others specially approved.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
